<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guitar Playing on RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/guitar-playing/</link><description>Recent content in Guitar Playing on RCJacH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/guitar-playing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3NS: The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/3ns-the-three-fundamental-finger-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/3ns-the-three-fundamental-finger-patterns/</guid><description>This post is part of the Three-Note-Per-String (3NS) Scale System series 1.Introduction
2.Ideology behind the 3NS Scale System
3.The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns
4.The Horizontal Transitions
5.Arpeggios
The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns Reminder of the main ideas In the last article, we talked about some of the basic observations regarding guitar fingering, and listed three essential sequences of diatonic scales and how we play them on one single string. We shall name them by their intervallic distance as SW (Semi-Whole), WS (Whole-Semi), and WW (Whole-Whole).</description></item><item><title>3NS: Ideology behind the 3NS System</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/3ns-ideology-behind-the-3ns-scale-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/3ns-ideology-behind-the-3ns-scale-system/</guid><description>This post is part of the Three-Note-Per-String (3NS) Scale System series 1.Introduction
2.Ideology behind the 3NS Scale System
3.The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns
4.The Horizontal Transitions
5.Arpeggios
Ideology behind the 3NS System What is special about 3NS system comparing to the CAGED system or others? NOTE: this is mainly an explanation of the why behind this system, if you want to get to the actual learning process right away, skip the follow content and go directly to The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns.</description></item><item><title>Three-Note-Per-String Scale System</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/three-note-per-string-scale-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/three-note-per-string-scale-system/</guid><description>This post is part of the Three-Note-Per-String (3NS) Scale System series 1.Introduction
2.Ideology behind the 3NS Scale System
3.The Three Fundamental Finger Patterns
4.The Horizontal Transitions
5.Arpeggios
Introduction Scales, up and down the neck, although necessary for making conscious musical decisions, are often regarded as tedious chores that kills passion and desires for music making. How long have you been practicing or struggling with them, learning all the positions, memorizing the fingerings for each position, and managing your way through the mistakes?</description></item><item><title>The Guitar Fretboard Exercise</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/the-guitar-fretboard-exercise/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/the-guitar-fretboard-exercise/</guid><description>Recently I have realized that a very important piece of information in the guitar category was missing from this blog, and that is fretboard familiarity to its fundamental element - knowing the note names on the fretboard. It is so vital that I would say this is THE ability required to making music consciously on guitar. Thus I wish to share it with you!
I believe the origin of this exercise was from Joe Satriani&amp;rsquo;s Colume in GUITAR For The Practicing Musicians magazine, which was collected into a book called the Guitar Secrets.</description></item><item><title>Single-String Scales</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/single-string-scales/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/single-string-scales/</guid><description>Introduction As guitarists, our exercises are filled with all kinds of diatonic and chromatic scales or chordscales, along with various techniques, licks, and comping methods. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to present a very efficient and effective method of practicing scales, and that is the Single-String Scales. This is a great way to getting familiar with the fretboard scale-wise, breaking out of the old habit of staying within a single position, and thinking more musically.</description></item><item><title>Guitar Strumming Patterns</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/guitar-strumming-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/guitar-strumming-patterns/</guid><description>For the test project which code explained in the last post, I have been doing midi mock ups of guitar strumming patterns, matching up the velocity, speed, and range to the audio files to get a sense of humanization. From the analysis and past guitar playing experiences, here are few tips on guitar strumming.
When strumming, most proficient guitarist work with subtractive method. Instead of counting where to strum, they have their hands moving up and down on the most active subdivisions and simply float over the strings without touching them when not strumming.</description></item></channel></rss>