<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music Production on RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/music-production/</link><description>Recent content in Music Production on RCJacH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:58:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/music-production/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working with Sample Sample Library Templates in REAPER</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/working-with-sample-library-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:58:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/working-with-sample-library-templates/</guid><description>This blog post functions as a prelude to my tutorial on setting up a Sample Library Server with REAPER. I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain why you would want to set one up by comparing several different approaches to templating with large sample libraries.
To understand the benefits of having a dedicated server for sample libraries, we need to look at some of the problems composers are facing when producing music.
Problems when Working with Sample Libraries Problems with Sample Libraries The problem with sample libraries lies in the size of ensembles and time required to set them up for professional production.</description></item><item><title>An Elaborated Summary of the Technique of Gain-Staging - 1. What and Why</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/gain-staging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:51:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/gain-staging/</guid><description>What is Gain-Staging Gain-staging is essentially the practice of managing all static volume settings with a fixed reference point. Static volume setting is decibels of gain added or subtracted to a signal at one place in the signal flow, which remains unchanged through out the time span of the project playback. The goal of gain-staging is to ensure that any pair of input and output signals enclosing a signal processor chain match in average volume.</description></item><item><title>REAPER Signal Flow</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</guid><description>What is signal flow?
For our interest in digital audio production, signal flow is how signal data, either audio or MIDI, travel through various stages of the DAW calculation.
Because of the potential complexity of our routing, from something as simple as building a send track to something more abstract such as designing modular synth or multi-track template with parameter modulations, to have a clear mental picture of the signal flow, it would be quite beneficial to know what stages and in what order our signals are going through within the DAW.</description></item><item><title>REAPER Toolbar System</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-toolbar-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-toolbar-system/</guid><description>I recently discovered an interesting and efficient way of using Reaper&amp;rsquo;s customizable toolbars.
In other DAWs, the toolbars would remain stagnant throughout the sessions, and the only change you can apply to them would be either to move them or hide them.
In Reaper, since we are lucky enough to have many customizable toolbars available, while able to customize our toolbars with any action, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take long before our screen becomes like this</description></item><item><title>Fundamental Guitar Voicings for Pian(o roll)ists</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/fundamental-guitar-voicing-for-piano-rollists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/fundamental-guitar-voicing-for-piano-rollists/</guid><description>For guitarist, from beginners to advanced players, there is a chord system called CAGED system, where you take the form of C, A, G, E, D barre chords and move them across the fretboard over different roots.
(img from http://www.cagedguitarsystem.net/)
So you only need to learn at most 5 basic chord shapes to start playing chord progressions on the guitar. However, for pianists, this concept might be a bit difficult to understand without basic guitar knowledge, and learning the guitar for a short time isn&amp;rsquo;t always the most efficient and effective method of approach to arranging for chordal playing on guitar.</description></item><item><title>How to Use Track Manager in REAPER</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-use-track-manager-in-reaper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-use-track-manager-in-reaper/</guid><description>When we are dealing with MIDI drumset, guitar, and other sample libraries that requires either multiple output or routing, the default setup may show up like this:
See the lines of space below the topmost track? That&amp;rsquo;s all the microphone outputs of a drum library. They display no audio information other than level meters, but taking up a huge chunk of space in the arranger view, especially when zoomed in. It will fire up your frustration during your working sessions, taking up scrolling time which you could have saved for music making, so we are better off throwing them out of our sight.</description></item><item><title>Recording Volume Calibration</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/recording-volume-calibration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/recording-volume-calibration/</guid><description>I have seen many people, from amateurs to professionals (in China), myself included, struggling with digital volume level calibration while tracking. Many people do not bother having a standard with levels and many lack the understanding of impact of leveling in tracking, resulting in level inconsistency between tracks or even takes. It took me quite a while to come across articles explaining at what level we should be recording at and why, and thus helped me greatly by providing recordings at consistent level while removing any doubts of &amp;ldquo;am I recording too hot or too quiet?</description></item></channel></rss>