<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workflow on RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in Workflow on RCJacH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>REAPER Toolbar System</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-toolbar-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-toolbar-system/</guid><description>I recently discovered an interesting and efficient way of using Reaper&amp;rsquo;s customizable toolbars.
In other DAWs, the toolbars would remain stagnant throughout the sessions, and the only change you can apply to them would be either to move them or hide them.
In Reaper, since we are lucky enough to have many customizable toolbars available, while able to customize our toolbars with any action, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take long before our screen becomes like this</description></item><item><title>REAPER Track Template - Layout RSGC</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a Reaper Track Template that I believe would improve your production workflow. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Layout RSGC&amp;rdquo;, which stands for Reference, Sections, Grooves, and Chords, a group of four tracks. These four tracks are used to construct a general layout for our song production, which is vital for commercial projects that is tight on schedule, with no time for any experimentation or trying out new ideas. It is way easier to insert the track template and copy n' pasting existing items rather than handwriting everything from scratch, which we may have been doing in the past.</description></item><item><title>How to Use Track Manager in REAPER</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-use-track-manager-in-reaper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-use-track-manager-in-reaper/</guid><description>When we are dealing with MIDI drumset, guitar, and other sample libraries that requires either multiple output or routing, the default setup may show up like this:
See the lines of space below the topmost track? That&amp;rsquo;s all the microphone outputs of a drum library. They display no audio information other than level meters, but taking up a huge chunk of space in the arranger view, especially when zoomed in. It will fire up your frustration during your working sessions, taking up scrolling time which you could have saved for music making, so we are better off throwing them out of our sight.</description></item></channel></rss>