<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rhythm on RCJacH</title>
    <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/rhythm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rhythm on RCJacH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/rhythm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to REALLY Use the Metronome</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-really-use-the-metronome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/how-to-really-use-the-metronome/</guid>
      <description>I was practicing keyboard one day with a metronome - the click-sounding machinery that&amp;rsquo;s been collecting dust on my shelf since purchase (I jest. I use software counterpart such as Bounce Metronome, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really collect dust when I never open it) - when lethargy struck. You know, the desire to withdraw from the current activity when it&amp;rsquo;s becoming repetitive and dull, or the urge to dawdle away upon facing difficult tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm in Hexadecimal - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/rhythm-in-hexadecimal-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/rhythm-in-hexadecimal-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing from part 1 of Rhythm in Hex.
THE TRIPLETS Done with the 4-note patterns, we can apply the same principle to the triplets as well, limiting to only 8 patterns in total, named: 0, 1, 2, 3, A, B, C, F. Can you guess which pattern each symbol represents?
Let&amp;rsquo;s review them in a list:
   4-note 3-Note Name       0     1     2     3     4     5     6     7     8     9     A     B     C     D     E     F    I&amp;rsquo;m sure all of you are thoughtful enough to realize the following problem: How do we distinguish the difference between 4-note pattern and 3-note pattern if they share the same name?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm in Hexadecimal - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/rhythm-in-hexadecimal-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/rhythm-in-hexadecimal-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Observation I&amp;rsquo;ve always been unfond of the typical academic rhythmic teachings around the world. Yes they do provide indepth explaination of rhythms in both macroscopic and microscopic level, however they lack a quick solution for the students that haven&amp;rsquo;t spent months or years of training in rhythm playing. Some twenty years ago in the western world, children are taught musicianship at a very early age, and with musical influence from the family and some spare practising time, they can get quite advanced in musical learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guitar Strumming Patterns</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/guitar-strumming-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/guitar-strumming-patterns/</guid>
      <description>For the test project which code explained in the last post, I have been doing midi mock ups of guitar strumming patterns, matching up the velocity, speed, and range to the audio files to get a sense of humanization. From the analysis and past guitar playing experiences, here are few tips on guitar strumming.
 When strumming, most proficient guitarist work with subtractive method. Instead of counting where to strum, they have their hands moving up and down on the most active subdivisions and simply float over the strings without touching them when not strumming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>