<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scripts &amp; Templates on RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/scripts-templates/</link><description>Recent content in Scripts &amp; Templates on RCJacH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/categories/scripts-templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>REAPER - RCMShip Perfect Pitch</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-rcmship-perfect-pitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-rcmship-perfect-pitch/</guid><description>Download from here: RCMShip Perfect Pitch on Github
or Simply add my repository in ReaPack:
RCJacH ReaPack Repository
Description RCMShip (MShip stands for musicianship) Perfect Pitch is a little game for exercising Perfect Pitch, the ability to recognize notes without any reference, using adaptive method of randomization.
How to Play Click START, the synth will play a tone. Guess the name of the tone by clicking on one of the note names.</description></item><item><title>Tone Sweep - REAPER JSFX Percussion Synth</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-tone-sweep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-tone-sweep/</guid><description>You can download it from here: Tone Sweep on Github
or Simply add my repository in ReaPack:
RCJacH ReaPack Repository
Description: This synth generates a monophonic sweeping tone when receiving a MIDI note input. Intended for designing percussive sounds, such as kicks, snares, toms, or sound FXs in electronic music genres.
Quick Instruction: Set a starting and ending note.
If necessary, change the Pitch Sweep Curve and length by dragging the Pitch Curve Graph, x axis for length, and y axis for curve.</description></item><item><title>REAPER JS: MIDI Note Beat Repeater</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-midi-note-beat-repeater/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-midi-note-beat-repeater/</guid><description>Download MIDI Note Beat Repeater JSFX and put it somewhere within the Effects folder of your Reaper Resources Path.
Update: Description: This script is made to emulate the note repeating function in Native Instrument Maschine hardware.
I have never used Maschine myself, thus I do not know how it really works.
However, I did watch some video that demonstrated great workflow for inputting hihat patterns.
How to use: You can use this script in two ways:</description></item><item><title>REAPER Track Template - Layout RSGC</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a Reaper Track Template that I believe would improve your production workflow. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Layout RSGC&amp;rdquo;, which stands for Reference, Sections, Grooves, and Chords, a group of four tracks. These four tracks are used to construct a general layout for our song production, which is vital for commercial projects that is tight on schedule, with no time for any experimentation or trying out new ideas. It is way easier to insert the track template and copy n' pasting existing items rather than handwriting everything from scratch, which we may have been doing in the past.</description></item><item><title>Vocal Recording &amp; Mixing Template by RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/vocal-recording-n-mixing-template-by-rcjach/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/vocal-recording-n-mixing-template-by-rcjach/</guid><description>Vocal Recording &amp;amp; Mixing Template
By RCJacH
Explanation Vocal Recording &amp;amp; Mixing Template by RCJacH is a REAPER template for recording and rough mixing lead vocal and vocal harmonies against an instrumental track, including native functional FXs (with a few JS effects) on each track with track controls directly visible on the mixer.
This template works the best with the default REAPER themes. All dynamic related FXs are designed to work around signals that are recorded with RMS level of -20dBFS.</description></item></channel></rss>