<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Midi on RCJacH</title>
    <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/midi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Midi on RCJacH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/midi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>REAPER Signal Flow</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</guid>
      <description>What is signal flow?
For our interest in digital audio production, signal flow is how signal data, either audio or MIDI, travel through various stages of the DAW calculation.
Because of the potential complexity of our routing, from something as simple as building a send track to something more abstract such as designing modular synth or multi-track template with parameter modulations, to have a clear mental picture of the signal flow, it would be quite beneficial to know what stages and in what order our signals are going through within the DAW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REAPER JS: MIDI Note Beat Repeater</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-midi-note-beat-repeater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-jsfx-midi-note-beat-repeater/</guid>
      <description>Download MIDI Note Beat Repeater JSFX and put it somewhere within the Effects folder of your Reaper Resources Path.
Update: * v1.1 (2016-10-09)
+ Renamed
+ Added Gate Function (Note Length)
+ Added Sync to grid function
# Fixed Note On accuracy
  Description: This script is made to emulate the note repeating function in Native Instrument Maschine hardware.
I have never used Maschine myself, thus I do not know how it really works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Guitar Voicings for Pian(o roll)ists</title>
      <link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/fundamental-guitar-voicing-for-piano-rollists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/fundamental-guitar-voicing-for-piano-rollists/</guid>
      <description>For guitarist, from beginners to advanced players, there is a chord system called CAGED system, where you take the form of C, A, G, E, D barre chords and move them across the fretboard over different roots.
(img from http://www.cagedguitarsystem.net/)
So you only need to learn at most 5 basic chord shapes to start playing chord progressions on the guitar. However, for pianists, this concept might be a bit difficult to understand without basic guitar knowledge, and learning the guitar for a short time isn&amp;rsquo;t always the most efficient and effective method of approach to arranging for chordal playing on guitar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>