<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recording on RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/recording/</link><description>Recent content in Recording on RCJacH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:51:01 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RCJacH.github.io/tags/recording/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Elaborated Summary of the Technique of Gain-Staging - 1. What and Why</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/an-elaborated-summary-of-the-technique-of-gain-staging-1.-what-and-why/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:51:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/an-elaborated-summary-of-the-technique-of-gain-staging-1.-what-and-why/</guid><description>What is Gain-Staging Gain-staging is essentially the practice of managing all static volume settings with a fixed reference point. Static volume setting is decibels of gain added or subtracted to a signal at one place in the signal flow, which remains unchanged through out the time span of the project playback. The goal of gain-staging is to ensure that any pair of input and output signals enclosing a signal processor chain match in average volume.</description></item><item><title>REAPER Signal Flow</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-signal-flow/</guid><description>What is signal flow?
For our interest in digital audio production, signal flow is how signal data, either audio or MIDI, travel through various stages of the DAW calculation.
Because of the potential complexity of our routing, from something as simple as building a send track to something more abstract such as designing modular synth or multi-track template with parameter modulations, to have a clear mental picture of the signal flow, it would be quite beneficial to know what stages and in what order our signals are going through within the DAW.</description></item><item><title>REAPER Track Template - Layout RSGC</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/reaper-track-template-layout-rsgc/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a Reaper Track Template that I believe would improve your production workflow. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Layout RSGC&amp;rdquo;, which stands for Reference, Sections, Grooves, and Chords, a group of four tracks. These four tracks are used to construct a general layout for our song production, which is vital for commercial projects that is tight on schedule, with no time for any experimentation or trying out new ideas. It is way easier to insert the track template and copy n&amp;rsquo; pasting existing items rather than handwriting everything from scratch, which we may have been doing in the past.</description></item><item><title>Vocal Recording &amp; Mixing Template by RCJacH</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/vocal-recording-mixing-template-by-rcjach/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/vocal-recording-mixing-template-by-rcjach/</guid><description>Vocal Recording &amp;amp; Mixing Template
By RCJacH
Explanation Vocal Recording &amp;amp; Mixing Template by RCJacH is a REAPER template for recording and rough mixing lead vocal and vocal harmonies against an instrumental track, including native functional FXs (with a few JS effects) on each track with track controls directly visible on the mixer.
This template works the best with the default REAPER themes. All dynamic related FXs are designed to work around signals that are recorded with RMS level of -20dBFS.</description></item><item><title>Recording Volume Calibration</title><link>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/recording-volume-calibration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RCJacH.github.io/blog/recording-volume-calibration/</guid><description>I have seen many people, from amateurs to professionals (in China), myself included, struggling with digital volume level calibration while tracking. Many people do not bother having a standard with levels and many lack the understanding of impact of leveling in tracking, resulting in level inconsistency between tracks or even takes. It took me quite a while to come across articles explaining at what level we should be recording at and why, and thus helped me greatly by providing recordings at consistent level while removing any doubts of &amp;ldquo;am I recording too hot or too quiet?</description></item></channel></rss>